hire.com 2018-11-23

# Privacy Policy

**(Effective Date:   September 25, 2018)**

The PeopleFluent companies (“PeopleFluent”) provide this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to explain how we collect, use and disclose certain personal information online on [ **www.PeopleFluent.com**](https://www.peoplefluent.com/) **,[www.SocialText.com](https://www.socialtext.com/)** and our web-based application services. It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. By using the Sites, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**Information We Collect**

PeopleFluent may collect information on its own behalf on the Sites as described in this Privacy Policy. PeopleFluent provides Web-based application services, software and related support services to help our customers manage information about and provide services to their employees, potential employees, contractors and others. 

The types of personal information we may collect about you through our sites include contact and identifying information (name, address, email address, phone and fax numbers, institution, title or job position), information about your interest in PeopleFluent products or services, information about your interest in newsletters, seminars, or other services that we provide (solely or jointly with others), information about any other transaction(s) between you or your organization and PeopleFluent and any other personal information that you may provide to us in an online form or through an email. Where we collect personal information through online forms, we will notify you of which fields are mandatory for the particular service or functionality you are requesting and which fields are optional. If you choose to provide information that is optional, we may use and disclose such information as described in this Privacy Policy.

A visitor to [ **www.PeopleFluent.com**](https://www.peoplefluent.com/) who is not seeking employment and not expressing an interest in purchasing products or services is not required to reveal any individually identifiable information such as name, address or telephone number. 

Through the use of cookies PeopleFluent collects information about the device or browser you are using to access our website. This includes your device’s IP address, cookie string data, and in the case of mobile devices, your device type and mobile device’s unique identifier. Please see the “opt out” functions under the Display Advertising and Retargeting Efforts on Third-Party Websites and Applications section.

Our customers may use our hosted application services to process data about their candidates, employees, contractors and agents. Personal data that PeopleFluent may maintain on behalf of our customers includes, but is not limited to, names, contact information, CV or resume, data of birth, national insurance numbers, social security numbers, compensation information, and race and ethnic origin. PeopleFluent does not own or control any of the information it processes on behalf of its customers. Such information is owned and controlled by the customer, and PeopleFluent receives such information merely as a processor on the customer’s behalf. We use such data only as authorized in our subscription agreements with such customers and in accordance with applicable law. Customers are responsible for maintaining the security of their own user logins.

If you are a customer of one of our Customers and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Customers that use our service, please contact the Customer that you interact with directly. We may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service.

**Testimonials**

PeopleFluent posts customer testimonials on its Web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer’s name. PeopleFluent obtains the customer’s consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you wish to remove your personal information that is being displayed on our public Web pages please send your request to [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com).

**Blog  **

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.  _To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at  _[ **Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com).  In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**  
Social Media Widgets**

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our website. These Features may collect your Internet protocol address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

**Newsletters**

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe by providing a functional unsubscribe mechanism in each email communication we send to users.

**Financial Information**

We may offer products or services and event or class registration for you to purchase online. To complete these online financial transactions, our sites may request personal information including contact information ([ **https://secure.peopleclick.com**](https://secure.peopleclick.com/) and [ **https://eeosource.peopleclick.com**](https://eeosource.peopleclick.com/)) and credit card billing information. Disclosure of this information is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.

**Surveys & Contests**

From time-to-time our sites may request personal information from you in connection with surveys or contests. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. Personal information requested may include contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code). Contact information will be used to notify the winners and award prizes, and may also be used to provide you with additional information about our products or services, or those of our selected business partners.

**Tracking Technologies**

PeopleFluent and our marketing partners, affiliates, or PeopleFluent-authorized service providers use cookies and similar technologies in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We track users’ use of our hosted Web-based application services to compile and analyze statistical and performance information about the application services and their use of the services. We use information about your use of the services for such purposes as making improvements to the services and communicating with you about new features or releases. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, ensure the checkbox for “Yes, I would like to be contacted with employment information” remains unchecked.

**Log Files and Aggregate Information**

PeopleFluent may record information that is not individually identifiable about how people access our Web sites and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses (or the DNS name associated with it), the Web site from which you are visiting PeopleFluent and the Web software you are using. This information is used in the aggregate, without disclosure of any individually identifiable information, to administer our system and make improvements to our site and to report to our customers and prospects on our sites’ performance. We reserve the right to share aggregate and anonymous information with potential partners and other third parties without restriction.

**Display Advertising and Retargeting Efforts on Third-Party Websites and Applications**

PeopleFluent has implemented and uses Display Advertising across third party websites and applications opted into the Google Content Network. Certain PeopleFluent advertisements on third party websites and applications in the Google Content Network may be retargeted using Google Analytics. Retargeting means that third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on a user’s past visits to our website.

We also partner with other third parties to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [ **here**](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [ **here**](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

**How Can I Opt Out of Google Analytics for Display Network or Retargeting?**

If you would like to be removed or blocked from Google Analytics For Display Network or from retargeting efforts there are several options:

  * Users can customize ad settings by using the [ **Ads Preferences Manager**](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/%E2%80%8E).
  * Users can apply the Google Analytics opt-out browser add on located at [ **https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).
  * If you would like to opt out of a specific cookie, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s opt out page [ **http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). (Or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).)

**Links**

PeopleFluent’s Web site may contain links to other Web sites. PeopleFluent is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites, and this Privacy Policy does not apply to such sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information.

**Disclosure**

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

We may disclose personal information including information collected for our clients, as necessary or appropriate in connection with any of the purposes for which we use personal information, including to subcontractors or service providers that help host or support the sites or otherwise provide technical assistance, fulfillment companies that help us to provide requested products or services and business partners that help conduct seminars or otherwise provide requested products, services or information. We may use third party service providers to provide credit card processing on our site. We will share your credit card information as necessary for the third party to provide such processing services. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the service agreements with our clients. We reserve the right to disclose personal information in connection with the sale or transfer of all or part of the business. In situations where we transfer personal information to these types of third parties, we require that such third parties must not use or disclose the information for any purposes other than those specified in this Privacy Policy, and that such third parties must maintain commercially reasonable security measures to protect the personal information. In situations involving the sale or transfer of all or part of the business, we will seek to notify users of the ownership change by way of a prominent notice posted on our Web site. We also reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and or in the good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, bankruptcy or similar legal process. PeopleFluent does not share, sell, rent, or trade personal information with third parties for their promotional purposes.

**Security**

To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of personal information, PeopleFluent has adopted appropriate physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the personal information we process. We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Data maintained by PeopleFluent is protected by computer security mechanisms including firewalls, encryption, monitoring software, data and network segmentation, and passwords. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number and your login information) on our order forms or application sites, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If, during their employment, PeopleFluent employees acquire confidential or proprietary information belonging to PeopleFluent or its customers, such information is required to be handled in confidence and may not be disclosed to unauthorized third parties. PeopleFluent employees are also responsible for the internal security of such information. PeopleFluent provides information and training to all employees who have access to data maintained on behalf of PeopleFluent customers. Employees who violate PeopleFluent security and safe maintenance of data policies are subject to appropriate discipline including, but not limited to, termination. If you have any questions about our security practices, you can email us at [ **Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com).

**EU-U.S. and SWISS-U.S. Privacy Shield**

PeopleFluent complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries (including Iceland, Liechtenstein, and Norway) and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. PeopleFluent has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [**https://www.privacyshield.gov/**](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list)

In certain situations, we may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

PeopleFluent’s accountability for personal data that it receives in the United States under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, PeopleFluent remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless PeopleFluent proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, PeopleFluent commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union and Swiss individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact PeopleFluent by email at [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@PeopleFluent.com) or via post at:

PeopleFluent

434 Fayetteville Street, 9th Floor

Attention: Security Team

Raleigh, North Carolina 27601

United States 

PeopleFluent has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit **<http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers>** for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you. 

PeopleFluent has further committed to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU in the context of the employment relationship.

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at [**https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction**](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction)

**To Unsubscribe or Modify Information**

Upon request Peoplefluent will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If you receive marketing or similar e-mail messages from us and you wish to opt out of receiving such messages, you may follow the opt-out procedure specified in the e-mail message or you may contact [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com). PeopleFluent intends to protect the quality and integrity of your personal information. If you wish to review, modify, correct and delete the information submitted to us directly, you should contact [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com).

PeopleFluent acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. If you are an applicant, employee or are otherwise affiliated with a PeopleFluent customer and wish to review or modify information provided to PeopleFluent via a PeopleFluent hosted service application, you should first contact the PeopleFluent customer to whom you submitted such information, or who has otherwise provided the information to PeopleFluent for processing. If such company is unable or unwilling to assist you, you should contact PeopleFluent at [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com)or to PeopleFluent Security at the contact information set out below.

Within 30 days of your request, Pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, EU and Swiss individuals have the right to obtain our confirmation of whether we maintain personal information relating to you in the United States. Upon request, we will provide you with reasonable access to the personal information that we hold about you. You may also correct, amend, or delete the personal information we hold about you where such information is inaccurate or has been processed in violation of the Principles. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data transferred to the United States under Privacy Shield, should direct their query to [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com). If requested to remove data, we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

We will retain your information and the information we process on behalf of our clients for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Where we are the ones that control the gathering and handling of the data, we will provide an individual opt-out choice, or opt-in for sensitive data, before we share your data with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To request to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com)

**Changes to this Web Site Privacy Policy**

PeopleFluent reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will re-post the revised policy here or at another location that is accessible from our home page so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personal information in a manner that is substantially different from that stated at the time we collected it, we will seek to notify users by way of an email, and provide users with a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner prior to the change becoming effective.

**Oversight/Enforcement**

PeopleFluent’s Information Security Officer is responsible for PeopleFluent’s compliance with and enforcement of this Privacy Policy; the Information Security Officer may be reached at [**Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com). The United States Federal Trade Commission is the statutory body that has jurisdiction to hear any claims against the organization regarding possible unfair or deceptive practices and violations of laws or regulations governing privacy.

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

PeopleFluent

434 Fayetteville Street, 9th Floor

Attention: Security Team

Raleigh, North Carolina 27601

United States

Phone: 1.877.820.4400

Fax: 1.919.645.2801

Email: [ **Security@PeopleFluent.com**](mailto:Security@peoplefluent.com)
